Email: bushrahafizkhan@gmail.com

Mobile: +61 437 916 634

I am an award winning, entrepreneurial & analytical blue-chip marketing leader with 15 years of experience across geographies and categories. My greatest strengths lie in collaborating with and motivating cross-functional teams and external partners to successfully accomplish ambitious strategic agendas via a blend of data, communication, optimization & innovation initiatives.

Career Highlights

- Global experience (South Asia, Africa, Middle East, Turkey, UK, US, South East Asia, Latin America and ANZ)
- Extensive category experience (Beauty, Hygiene, Consumer Devices, and Laundry) in global, regional, and local roles
- Led and motivated geographically dispersed cross-functional teams (R&D, SC, Sales, Consumer Research, Media)
- Successfully launched brand/category "firsts" & geo white-space expansion (hygiene in US, new laundry format in ANZ)
- Set & executed winning brand & portfolio strategy (established haircare dominance in South East Asia)
- Award winning marketing campaigns (Unilever Global Award & local media recognition for handwashing campaign)

Key Skills in Action

- Entrepreneurial Growth Seeker identified key underserved consumer segment (1.2bn Muslims) via research that could step change growth & profitability. Proposed, created, and executed award winning innovation & communication mix that became a Unilever benchmark for inclusively serving diverse consumer needs
- Savvy stakeholder management convinced senior retailer leadership of the merits of the capsules segment in the laundry category via a series of presentations demonstrating consumer & category evolution
- **Digital Native** collaborated with Google teams to create authentic digital-first COVID-19 campaign that beat global brand-lift study benchmarks and has become Henkel template for digital campaigns
- Analytical regularly devised & reviewed research studies across multiple geographies with aim to find sizable niches as well as regional or global behaviour patterns to synergize innovation and communication efforts
- Relationship Based Leader aligned disparate country agendas in South East Asia behind a winning cluster-wide hair care strategy by intensive consumer studies, listening to local leadership and proposing a plan based on business & consumer similarities rather than fragmentation

Skills, Abilities & Experience

Marketing & Brand Management

- Comms & Campaign Development: Created award winning campaigns validated by consumers across Hair Care, Hygiene, Oral Care & Laundry by delivering brand growth. An example is a full marketing mix developed for Tresseme in South East Asia that unlocked cluster-wide penetration by tapping into local consumer beauty insights
- Budget Management: Adept at managing budgets to not only drive business growth but also deliver savings. In the
 Unilever Hygiene segment, I successfully managed Global Media Spend of USD \$20M+ across a portfolio of brands and
 drove \$1m+ savings via driving media & channel selection efficiencies. In addition, I optimized brand innovation budget of
 \$10M+ in collaboration with supply chain to improve brand profitability by 100bps
- **Digital Expertise:** I have a long association with digitally connecting brands & consumers. Most recently for the Henkel laundry portfolio, I developed and executed multiple digital campaigns across countries involving creation of brand websites, microsites, YouTube campaigns (directors mix), retailer CRM & loyalty partnerships and video on demand which shifted brand equity positively, generating brand love and resulted in an increase in sales.
- Innovation: Highly skilled at managing innovation from inception through to execution resulting in winning mixes for consumers, retailers, and brands. For Cold Power, Henkel's largest brand, I have introduced radical capsule innovations resulting in significant category shifts, upgrading consumers to more convenient, yet profitable formats. In addition, I have driven trial by launching penetration packs resulting in consumer conversion and growth.

Commercial Acumen

• Turnaround: With my mix of strategic thinking and commercial acumen, I am a brand turnaround specialist. A recent example is the Henkel ANZ laundry business where I have revived a declining business to growth (-3% to +20%) by identifying the right category portfolio best suited to consumer needs and in parallel driven supply chain efficiency and savings of over \$3M

Organizational Savvy

• Stakeholder Management: I have worked in and successfully navigated complex matrix organizations for over 15 years involving multi-function, multi-country stakeholder models. This requires a clear strategic point of view coupled with the ability to listen to, influence and align stakeholders with disparate agendas behind a coherent plan

- **Project Management:** Over the course of my career, I have launched 40+ innovations (including fast track launches seed to launch in 4 months) across multiple countries and categories. These projects have delivered growth for the business by genuinely addressing consumer needs, but also by disciplined project management that kept team stakeholder focus and landed them on time-in full often in volatile, uncertain, complex, and ambiguous environments
- Communication & Presentation Skills: The nature of my roles has finely honed my communication and presentation skills by regular internal and external senior stakeholders engagement (such as category presidents & retail heads) to pitch, update and prioritize my projects and strategic agenda.

Leadership

Team motivation & management: I have an inclusive, empowering leadership style that ensures clarity on team agenda
and what winning looks like for every single member on my team. I have managed a team ranging from 1 – 5 over the last
decade, winning through leading, motivating, inspiring, and coaching. I take great pride in knowing that my team members
have been promoted and awarded regularly.

Data Driven

• Attributable Campaigns: I believe in communication that connects with consumer hearts but comes from and is targeted by deep interrogation of consumer data. In all my roles I have championed the use of digital media to arrive at optimizable campaigns with attributable sales uplifts. Where data exists, I use it; where it does not, I seek third party or proxy variables to substantiate or dispel my growth hypotheses and then track and optimize ruthlessly

Employment History

Henkel ANZ - Head of Digital & Premium | May 2019 - Current

- Leading premium laundry portfolio across ANZ including communication, innovation, and full P&L responsibility
- Category Digital Lead for total Business Unit partnering with internal teams and agencies to elevate mix delivery
- Led biggest brand relaunch in the history of the category in ANZ resulting in double digit business growth despite COVID

Unilever ANZ - Strategic Consultant Hair Care | March 2019 - May 2019

- Leading the Styling Category across ANZ for 5 leading Hair Care brands and leading digital development
- Partnered with local influencers & New York Fashion Week to livestream latest hair & fashion trends in ANZ
- Developed ambitious 2X/3yrs styling portfolio strategy by digitizing & addressing changing millennial media consumption

Unilever Asia

Global Marketing Manager TRESemmé | April 2017 – Jan 2019

- Leading premiumization in the Hair Care Category in South East Asia & Regional E-comm lead
- Digital lead for the category creating digital-first assets for regional premium innovation campaigns
- Led global contract negotiations for communication featuring celebrities such as Kendall Jenner & Gal Gadot

Senior Global Brand Manager Lifebuoy | April 2014 - Mar 2017

- Platform leader for 2nd largest format & geography. Driving ethnic and geographic white space entries for brand
- Developed award winning & global Unilever best practice hygiene campaign for Indonesia & Pakistan
- Developed & fast-tracked delivery of compelling Ramadan mix (from insight to on-air within 3 months)

Regional Brand Manager Oral Care | May 2011 - Mar 2014

Unilever Arabia - Regional Assistant Brand Manager | May 2008 - April 2011

Unilever Pakistan – Assistant Brand Manager | Jan 2004 – Sep 2006

Qualifications

Columbia Business School, USA

Digital Marketing: Customer Engagement, Social Media, Planning & Analytics

Cass Business School, UK

MSc of Management – Major: Marketing. Graduated with Distinction – top10% of class

Mount Holyoke College, USA

Bachelor of Arts - Major: Economics, Minors: Math